Name

glBindTexture — bind a named texture to a texturing target

C Specification

void glBindTexture( | GLenum   | target,
  | GLuint   | texture);

Parameters

target

Specifies the target to which the texture is bound. Must be either GL_TEXTURE_1D, GL_TEXTURE_2D, GL_TEXTURE_3D, or GL_TEXTURE_CUBE_MAP.

texture

Specifies the name of a texture.

Description

glBindTexture lets you create or use a named texture. Calling glBindTexture with target set to GL_TEXTURE_1D, GL_TEXTURE_2D, GL_TEXTURE_3D or GL_TEXTURE_CUBE_MAP and texture set to the name of the new texture binds the texture name to the target. When a texture is bound to a target, the previous binding for that target is automatically broken.

Texture names are unsigned integers. The value zero is reserved to represent the default texture for each texture target. Texture names and the corresponding texture contents are local to the shared display-list space (see glXCreateContext) of the current GL rendering context; two rendering contexts share texture names only if they also share display lists.

You may use glGenTextures to generate a set of new texture names.

When a texture is first bound, it assumes the specified target: A texture first bound to GL_TEXTURE_1D becomes one-dimensional texture, a texture first bound to GL_TEXTURE_2D becomes two-dimensional texture, a texture first bound to GL_TEXTURE_3D becomes three-dimensional texture, and a texture first bound to GL_TEXTURE_CUBE_MAP becomes a cube-mapped texture. The state of a one-dimensional texture immediately after it is first bound is equivalent to the state of the default GL_TEXTURE_1D at GL initialization, and similarly for two- and three-dimensional textures and cube-mapped textures.

While a texture is bound, GL operations on the target to which it is bound affect the bound texture, and queries of the target to which it is bound return state from the bound texture. If texture mapping is active on the target to which a texture is bound, the bound texture is used. In effect, the texture targets become aliases for the textures currently bound to them, and the texture name zero refers to the default textures that were bound to them at initialization.

A texture binding created with glBindTexture remains active until a different texture is bound to the same target, or until the bound texture is deleted with glDeleteTextures.

Once created, a named texture may be re-bound to its same original target as often as needed. It is usually much faster to use glBindTexture to bind an existing named texture to one of the texture targets than it is to reload the texture image using glTexImage1D, glTexImage2D, or glTexImage3D. For additional control over performance, use glPrioritizeTextures.

glBindTexture is included in display lists.

Notes

glBindTexture is available only if the GL version is 1.1 or greater.

GL_TEXTURE_CUBE_MAP is available only if the GL version is 1.3 or greater.

Errors

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if target is not one of the allowable values.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if texture was previously created with a target that doesn't match that of target.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glBindTexture is executed between the execution of glBegin and the corresponding execution of glEnd.

Associated Gets

glGet with argument GL_TEXTURE_BINDING_1D

glGet with argument GL_TEXTURE_BINDING_2D

glGet with argument GL_TEXTURE_BINDING_3D

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glAreTexturesResident, glDeleteTextures, glGenTextures, glGet, glGetTexParameter, glIsTexture, glPrioritizeTextures, glTexImage1D, glTexImage2D, glTexParameter

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see https://web.archive.org/web/20171022161616/http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glCreateProgram — Creates a program object

C Specification

GLuint glCreateProgram( |   | void);

Description

glCreateProgram creates an empty program object and returns a non-zero value by which it can be referenced. A program object is an object to which shader objects can be attached. This provides a mechanism to specify the shader objects that will be linked to create a program. It also provides a means for checking the compatibility of the shaders that will be used to create a program (for instance, checking the compatibility between a vertex shader and a fragment shader). When no longer needed as part of a program object, shader objects can be detached.

One or more executables are created in a program object by successfully attaching shader objects to it with glAttachShader, successfully compiling the shader objects with glCompileShader, and successfully linking the program object with glLinkProgram. These executables are made part of current state when glUseProgram is called. Program objects can be deleted by calling glDeleteProgram. The memory associated with the program object will be deleted when it is no longer part of current rendering state for any context.

Notes

glCreateProgram is available only if the GL version is 2.0 or greater.

Like display lists and texture objects, the name space for program objects may be shared across a set of contexts, as long as the server sides of the contexts share the same address space. If the name space is shared across contexts, any attached objects and the data associated with those attached objects are shared as well.

Applications are responsible for providing the synchronization across API calls when objects are accessed from different execution threads.

Errors

This function returns 0 if an error occurs creating the program object.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glCreateProgram is executed between the execution of glBegin and the corresponding execution of glEnd.

Associated Gets

glGet with the argument GL_CURRENT_PROGRAM

glGetActiveAttrib with a valid program object and the index of an active attribute variable

glGetActiveUniform with a valid program object and the index of an active uniform variable

glGetAttachedShaders with a valid program object

glGetAttribLocation with a valid program object and the name of an attribute variable

glGetProgram with a valid program object and the parameter to be queried

glGetProgramInfoLog with a valid program object

glGetUniform with a valid program object and the location of a uniform variable

glGetUniformLocation with a valid program object and the name of a uniform variable

glIsProgram

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glAttachShader, glBindAttribLocation, glCreateShader, glDeleteProgram, glDetachShader, glLinkProgram, glUniform, glUseProgram, glValidateProgram

Copyright

Copyright © 2003-2005 3Dlabs Inc. Ltd. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. https://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glFlush — force execution of GL commands in finite time

C Specification

void glFlush( |   | void);

Description

Different GL implementations buffer commands in several different locations, including network buffers and the graphics accelerator itself. glFlush empties all of these buffers, causing all issued commands to be executed as quickly as they are accepted by the actual rendering engine. Though this execution may not be completed in any particular time period, it does complete in finite time.

Because any GL program might be executed over a network, or on an accelerator that buffers commands, all programs should call glFlush whenever they count on having all of their previously issued commands completed. For example, call glFlush before waiting for user input that depends on the generated image.

Notes

glFlush can return at any time. It does not wait until the execution of all previously issued GL commands is complete.

Errors

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glFlush is executed between the execution of glBegin and the corresponding execution of glEnd.

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glFinish

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see https://web.archive.org/web/20171022161616/http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glGetVertexAttribPointerv — return the address of the specified generic vertex attribute pointer

C Specification

void glGetVertexAttribPointerv( | GLuint   | index,
  | GLenum   | pname,
  | GLvoid **  | pointer);

Parameters

index

Specifies the generic vertex attribute parameter to be returned.

pname

Specifies the symbolic name of the generic vertex attribute parameter to be returned. Must be GL_VERTEX_ATTRIB_ARRAY_POINTER.

pointer

Returns the pointer value.

Description

glGetVertexAttribPointerv returns pointer information. index is the generic vertex attribute to be queried, pname is a symbolic constant indicating the pointer to be returned, and params is a pointer to a location in which to place the returned data.

If a non-zero named buffer object was bound to the GL_ARRAY_BUFFER target (see glBindBuffer) when the desired pointer was previously specified, the pointer returned is a byte offset into the buffer object's data store.

Notes

glGetVertexAttribPointerv is available only if the GL version is 2.0 or greater.

The pointer returned is client-side state.

The initial value for each pointer is 0.

Errors

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if index is greater than or equal to GL_MAX_VERTEX_ATTRIBS.

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if pname is not an accepted value.

Associated Gets

glGet with argument GL_MAX_VERTEX_ATTRIBS

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glGetVertexAttrib, glVertexAttribPointer

Copyright

Copyright © 2003-2005 3Dlabs Inc. Ltd. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. https://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glHint — specify implementation-specific hints

C Specification

void glHint( | GLenum   | target,
  | GLenum   | mode);

Parameters

target

Specifies a symbolic constant indicating the behavior to be controlled. GL_FOG_HINT, GL_GENERATE_MIPMAP_HINT, GL_LINE_SMOOTH_HINT, GL_PERSPECTIVE_CORRECTION_HINT, GL_POINT_SMOOTH_HINT, GL_POLYGON_SMOOTH_HINT, GL_TEXTURE_COMPRESSION_HINT, and GL_FRAGMENT_SHADER_DERIVATIVE_HINT are accepted.

mode

Specifies a symbolic constant indicating the desired behavior. GL_FASTEST, GL_NICEST, and GL_DONT_CARE are accepted.

Description

Certain aspects of GL behavior, when there is room for interpretation, can be controlled with hints. A hint is specified with two arguments. target is a symbolic constant indicating the behavior to be controlled, and mode is another symbolic constant indicating the desired behavior. The initial value for each target is GL_DONT_CARE. mode can be one of the following:

GL_FASTEST

The most efficient option should be chosen.

GL_NICEST

The most correct, or highest quality, option should be chosen.

GL_DONT_CARE

No preference.

Though the implementation aspects that can be hinted are well defined, the interpretation of the hints depends on the implementation. The hint aspects that can be specified with target, along with suggested semantics, are as follows:

GL_FOG_HINT

Indicates the accuracy of fog calculation. If per-pixel fog calculation is not efficiently supported by the GL implementation, hinting GL_DONT_CARE or GL_FASTEST can result in per-vertex calculation of fog effects.

GL_FRAGMENT_SHADER_DERIVATIVE_HINT

Indicates the accuracy of the derivative calculation for the GL shading language fragment processing built-in functions: dFdx, dFdy, and fwidth.

GL_GENERATE_MIPMAP_HINT

Indicates the quality of filtering when generating mipmap images.

GL_LINE_SMOOTH_HINT

Indicates the sampling quality of antialiased lines. If a larger filter function is applied, hinting GL_NICEST can result in more pixel fragments being generated during rasterization.

GL_PERSPECTIVE_CORRECTION_HINT

Indicates the quality of color, texture coordinate, and fog coordinate interpolation. If perspective-corrected parameter interpolation is not efficiently supported by the GL implementation, hinting GL_DONT_CARE or GL_FASTEST can result in simple linear interpolation of colors and/or texture coordinates.

GL_POINT_SMOOTH_HINT

Indicates the sampling quality of antialiased points. If a larger filter function is applied, hinting GL_NICEST can result in more pixel fragments being generated during rasterization.

GL_POLYGON_SMOOTH_HINT

Indicates the sampling quality of antialiased polygons. Hinting GL_NICEST can result in more pixel fragments being generated during rasterization, if a larger filter function is applied.

GL_TEXTURE_COMPRESSION_HINT

Indicates the quality and performance of the compressing texture images. Hinting GL_FASTEST indicates that texture images should be compressed as quickly as possible, while GL_NICEST indicates that texture images should be compressed with as little image quality loss as possible. GL_NICEST should be selected if the texture is to be retrieved by glGetCompressedTexImage for reuse.

Notes

The interpretation of hints depends on the implementation. Some implementations ignore glHint settings.

GL_TEXTURE_COMPRESSION_HINT is available only if the GL version is 1.3 or greater.

GL_GENERATE_MIPMAP_HINT is available only if the GL version is 1.4 or greater.

GL_FRAGMENT_SHADER_DERIVATIVE_HINT is available only if the GL version is 2.0 or greater.

Errors

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if either target or mode is not an accepted value.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glHint is executed between the execution of glBegin and the corresponding execution of glEnd.

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see https://web.archive.org/web/20171022161616/http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

gluGetString — return a string describing the GLU version or GLU extensions

C Specification

const GLubyte * gluGetString( | GLenum   | name);

Parameters

name

Specifies a symbolic constant, one of GLU_VERSION, or GLU_EXTENSIONS.

Description

gluGetString returns a pointer to a static string describing the GLU version or the GLU extensions that are supported.

The version number is one of the following forms:

major_number.minor_number major_number.minor_number.release_number.

The version string is of the following form:

version number<space>vendor-specific information

Vendor-specific information is optional. Its format and contents depend on the implementation.

The standard GLU contains a basic set of features and capabilities. If a company or group of companies wish to support other features, these may be included as extensions to the GLU. If name is GLU_EXTENSIONS, then gluGetString returns a space-separated list of names of supported GLU extensions. (Extension names never contain spaces.)

All strings are null-terminated.

Notes

gluGetString only returns information about GLU extensions. Call glGetString to get a list of GL extensions.

gluGetString is an initialization routine. Calling it after a glNewList results in undefined behavior.

Errors

NULL is returned if name is not GLU_VERSION or GLU_EXTENSIONS.

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glGetString

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see https://web.archive.org/web/20171022161616/http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

gluTessNormal — specify a normal for a polygon

C Specification

void gluTessNormal( | GLUtesselator*   | tess,
  | GLdouble   | valueX,
  | GLdouble   | valueY,
  | GLdouble   | valueZ);

Parameters

tess

Specifies the tessellation object (created with gluNewTess).

valueX

Specifies the first component of the normal.

valueY

Specifies the second component of the normal.

valueZ

Specifies the third component of the normal.

Description

gluTessNormal describes a normal for a polygon that the program is defining. All input data will be projected onto a plane perpendicular to one of the three coordinate axes before tessellation and all output triangles will be oriented CCW with respect to the normal (CW orientation can be obtained by reversing the sign of the supplied normal). For example, if you know that all polygons lie in the x-y plane, call gluTessNormal(tess, 0.0, 0.0, 1.0) before rendering any polygons.

If the supplied normal is (0.0, 0.0, 0.0) (the initial value), the normal is determined as follows. The direction of the normal, up to its sign, is found by fitting a plane to the vertices, without regard to how the vertices are connected. It is expected that the input data lies approximately in the plane; otherwise, projection perpendicular to one of the three coordinate axes may substantially change the geometry. The sign of the normal is chosen so that the sum of the signed areas of all input contours is nonnegative (where a CCW contour has positive area).

The supplied normal persists until it is changed by another call to gluTessNormal.

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

gluTessBeginPolygon, gluTessEndPolygon

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see https://web.archive.org/web/20171022161616/http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glXCreateNewContext — create a new GLX rendering context

C Specification

GLXContext glXCreateNewContext( | Display *   | dpy,
  | GLXFBConfig   | config,
  | int   | render_type,
  | GLXContext   | share_list,
  | Bool   | direct);

Parameters

dpy

Specifies the connection to the X server.

config

Specifies the GLXFBConfig structure with the desired attributes for the context.

render_type

Specifies the type of the context to be created. Must be one of GLX_RGBA_TYPE or GLX_COLOR_INDEX_TYPE.

share_list

Specifies the context with which to share display lists. NULL indicates that no sharing is to take place.

share_list

Specifies whether rendering is to be done with a direct connection to the graphics system if possible (True) or through the X server (False).

Description

glXCreateNewContext creates a GLX rendering context and returns its handle. This context can be used to render into GLX windows, pixmaps, or pixel buffers. If glXCreateNewContext fails to create a rendering context, NULL is returned.

If render_type is GLX_RGBA_TYPE, then a context that supports RGBA rendering is created. If config is GLX_COLOR_INDEX_TYPE, then context supporting color-index rendering is created.

If render_type is not NULL, then all display-list indexes and definitions are shared by context render_type and by the newly created context. An arbitrary number of contexts can share a single display-list space. However, all rendering contexts that share a single display-list space must themselves exist in the same address space. Two rendering contexts share an address space if both are nondirect using the same server, or if both are direct and owned by a single process. Note that in the nondirect case, it is not necessary for the calling threads to share an address space, only for their related rendering contexts to share an address space.

If share_list is True, then a direct-rendering context is created if the implementation supports direct rendering, if the connection is to an X server that is local, and if a direct-rendering context is available. (An implementation may return an indirect context when share_list is True.) If share_list is False, then a rendering context that renders through the X server is always created. Direct rendering provides a performance advantage in some implementations. However, direct-rendering contexts cannot be shared outside a single process, and they may be unable to render to GLX pixmaps.

Notes

glXCreateNewContext is available only if the GLX version is 1.3 or greater.

If the GLX version is 1.1 or 1.0, the GL version must be 1.0. If the GLX version is 1.2, then the GL version must be 1.1. If the GLX version is 1.3, then the GL version must be 1.2.

Errors

NULL is returned if execution fails on the client side.

GLXBadContext is generated if render_type is not a GLX context and is not NULL.

GLXBadFBConfig is generated if config is not a valid GLXFBConfig.

BadMatch is generated if the context to be created would not share the address space or the screen of the context specified by render_type.

BadAlloc is generated if the server does not have enough resources to allocate the new context.

BadValue is generated if config is not a valid visual (for example, if a particular GLX implementation does not support it).

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glXChooseFBConfig, glXCreateContext, glXDestroyContext, glXGetFBConfigs, glXGetFBConfigAttrib, glXIsDirect, glXMakeContextCurrent

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see https://web.archive.org/web/20171022161616/http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glXGetClientString — return a string describing the client

C Specification

const char * glXGetClientString( | Display *   | dpy,
  | int   | name);

Parameters

dpy

Specifies the connection to the X server.

name

Specifies which string is returned. The symbolic constants GLX_VENDOR, GLX_VERSION, and GLX_EXTENSIONS are accepted.

Description

glXGetClientString returns a string describing some aspect of the client library. The possible values for name are GLX_VENDOR, GLX_VERSION, and GLX_EXTENSIONS. If name is not set to one of these values, glXGetClientString returns NULL. The format and contents of the vendor string is implementation dependent.

The extensions string is null-terminated and contains a space-separated list of extension names. (The extension names never contain spaces.) If there are no extensions to GLX, then the empty string is returned.

The version string is laid out as follows:

<major_version.minor_version><space><vendor-specific info>

Both the major and minor portions of the version number are of arbitrary length. The vendor-specific information is optional. However, if it is present, the format and contents are implementation specific.

Notes

glXGetClientString is available only if the GLX version is 1.1 or greater.

If the GLX version is 1.1 or 1.0, the GL version must be 1.0. If the GLX version is 1.2, then the GL version must be 1.1. If the GLX version is 1.3, then the GL version must be 1.2.

glXGetClientString only returns information about GLX extensions supported by the client. Call glGetString to get a list of GL extensions supported by the server.

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glXQueryVersion, glXQueryExtensionsString, glXQueryServerString

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see https://web.archive.org/web/20171022161616/http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glXImportContextEXT — import another process's indirect rendering context.

C Specification

GLXContext glXImportContextEXT( | Display *   | dpy,
  | GLXContextID   | contextID);

Parameters

dpy

Specifies the connection to the X server.

contextID

Specifies a GLX rendering context.

Description

glXImportContextEXT creates a GLXContext given the XID of an existing GLXContext. It may be used in place of glXCreateContext, to share another process's indirect rendering context.

Only the server-side context information can be shared between X clients; client-side state, such as pixel storage modes, cannot be shared. Thus, glXImportContextEXT must allocate memory to store client-side information. This memory is freed by calling glXFreeContextEXT.

This call does not create a new XID. It merely makes an existing object available to the importing client (Display *). Like any XID, it goes away when the creating client drops its connection or the ID is explicitly deleted. Note that this is when the XID goes away. The object goes away when the XID goes away AND the context is not current to any thread.

If contextID refers to a direct rendering context then no error is generated but glXImportContextEXT returns NULL.

glXImportContextEXT is part of the EXT_import_context extension, not part of the core GLX command set. If _glxextstring(EXT_import_context) is included in the string returned by glXQueryExtensionsString, when called with argument GLX_EXTENSIONS, extension EXT_import_context is supported.

Errors

GLXBadContext is generated if contextID does not refer to a valid context.

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glXCreateContext, glXQueryVersion, glXQueryExtensionsString, glXGetContextIDEXT, glXFreeContextEXT

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see https://web.archive.org/web/20171022161616/http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glXSelectEvent — select GLX events for a window or a GLX pixel buffer

C Specification

void glXSelectEvent( | Display *   | dpy,
  | GLXDrawable   | draw,
  | unsigned long   | event_mask);

Parameters

dpy

Specifies the connection to the X server.

draw

Specifies a GLX drawable. Must be a GLX pixel buffer or a window.

event_mask

Specifies the events to be returned for draw.

Description

glXSelectEvent sets the GLX event mask for a GLX pixel buffer or a window. Calling glXSelectEvent overrides any previous event mask that was set by the client for draw. Note that it does not affect the event masks that other clients may have specified for draw since each client rendering to draw has a separate event mask for it.

Currently, only one GLX event, GLX_PBUFFER_CLOBBER_MASK, can be selected. The following data is returned to the client when a GLX_PBUFFER_CLOBBER_MASK event occurs:

typedef struct {

int event_type; | /* GLX_DAMAGED or GLX_SAVED */
int draw_type; | /* GLX_WINDOW or GLX_PBUFFER */
unsigned long serial; | /* # of last request processed by server */
Bool send_event; | /* true if this came for SendEvent request */
Display *display; | /* display the event was read from */
GLXDrawable drawable; | /* i.d. of Drawable */
unsigned int buffer_mask; | /* mask indicating affected buffers */
int x, y; |
int width, height; |
int count; | /* if nonzero, at least this many more */

} GLXPbufferClobberEvent; The valid bit masks used in buffer_mask are:

Bitmask | Corresponding Buffer
GLX_FRONT_LEFT_BUFFER_BIT | Front left color buffer
GLX_FRONT_RIGHT_BUFFER_BIT | Front right color buffer
GLX_BACK_LEFT_BUFFER_BIT | Back left color buffer
GLX_BACK_RIGHT_BUFFER_BIT | Back right color buffer
GLX_AUX_BUFFERS_BIT | Auxiliary buffer
GLX_DEPTH_BUFFER_BIT | Depth buffer
GLX_STENCIL_BUFFER_BIT | Stencil buffer
GLX_ACCUM_BUFFER_BIT | Accumulation buffer

A single X server operation can cause several buffer clobber events to be sent. (e.g., a single GLX pixel buffer may be damaged and cause multiple buffer clobber events to be generated). Each event specifies one region of the GLX drawable that was affected by the X Server operation. The buffer_mask field indicates which color buffers and ancillary buffers were affected. All the buffer clobber events generated by a single X server action are guaranteed to be contiguous in the event queue. The conditions under which this event is generated and the event_type varies, depending on the type of the GLX drawable.

When the GLX_AUX_BUFFERS_BIT is set in buffer_mask, then aux_buffer is set to indicate which buffer was affected. If more than one aux buffer was affected, then additional events are generated as part of the same contiguous event group. Each additional event will have only the GLX_AUX_BUFFERS_BIT set in buffer_mask, and the aux_buffer field will be set appropriately. For nonstereo drawables, GLX_FRONT_LEFT_BUFFER_BIT and GLX_BACK_LEFT_BUFFER_BIT are used to specify the front and back color buffers.

For preserved GLX pixel buffers, a buffer clobber event with type GLX_SAVED is generated whenever the contents of the GLX pixel buffer is moved out of offscreen memory. The event(s) describes which portions of the GLX pixel buffer were affected. Clients who receive many buffer clobber events, referring to different save actions, should consider freeing the GLX pixel buffer resource in order to prevent the system from thrashing due to insufficient resources.

For an unpreserved GLXPbuffer, a buffer clobber event, with type GLX_DAMAGED, is generated whenever a portion of the GLX pixel buffer becomes invalid. The client may wish to regenerate the invalid portions of the GLX pixel buffer.

For Windows, buffer clobber events, with type GLX_SAVED, occur whenever an ancillary buffer, associated with the window, gets clobbered or moved out of off-screen memory. The event contains information indicating which color buffers and ancillary buffers\(emand which portions of those buffers\(emwere affected.

Notes

glXSelectEvent is available only if the GLX version is 1.3 or greater.

If the GLX version is 1.1 or 1.0, the GL version must be 1.0. If the GLX version is 1.2, then the GL version must be 1.1. If the GLX version is 1.3, then the GL version must be 1.2.

Errors

GLXBadDrawable is generated if draw is not a valid window or a valid GLX pixel buffer.

Associated Gets

glXGetSelectedEvent

{$pipelinestall}{$examples}

See Also

glXCreatePbuffer

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see https://web.archive.org/web/20171022161616/http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.